# Andre Barreto Chicago - IL - 60660 - U.S.A

**5823 N. Ravenswood Ave #203** 

**Phone**: (773) 607-9056

**Email:** andrelbarreto@yahoo.com.br

#### Education

Northwestern University Coding Bootcamp Fullstack Flex Class of 2020 Learning full stack web development including HTML, CSS & Bootstrap, Jscrip, Jquery, Nodejs, React, among others.

Career Academy SENAC University, Brazil UNESP Bauru, Brazil. UNICAMP // COTIL Project Management Certification (2017)
Bachelors Degree in Hospitality
Communications – Journalism
Diploma in Computer Technology

# **Summary**

Accomplished multicultural marketing communications professional with over ten years of consumer products and services experience seeking position that can use experience and skills. Solid academic and practical background in marketing and event planning. Polyglot with written, oral and public speaking communication skills in English, Portuguese and Spanish as well as basic Italian and French. Skillful marketing strategist and adept sales account tactician. Demonstrated record of proficiency, accuracy, leadership and human relations. Proven record with several Fortune 500 Companies including Disney, Nintendo, Pepsi, Ford, Verizon Wireless, Bank of America, McDonald's, Sony and others.

## **Experience**

# Mosaic for Google - Google Hardware Store Bucktown

Google Guide for Pop-up Experience in Chicago

September 2018/ January 2019

### The Marketing Arm

### Nintendo Switch / 3DS Holiday Mall Chicago

Nintendo Holiday Marketing Programing Manager

October 2018/ December 2018

# Nintendo Switch Holiday Experience Miami

Nintendo Holiday Marketing Programing Manager

October 2017/ December 2017

As a Field Programing Manager helped launch the first Switch Experience at Aventura Mall, trained local brand ambassadors on hardware and software titles and oversaw load-in and load-out as well as daily operations. Programed special events and tournaments, including social media and printed advertising for those. Created detailed reports with photos daily and weekly.

Talentline May 2017 – August 2017

Samsung Galaxy Lounge Chicago

Assistant Manager

Talentline November 2016 – January 2017

Samsung Reboot Mall Program T.L. - Chicago

**Motive Group** 

Mist Twst Tour Manager – California May 2016 – October 2016

SALESFORCE WORLD TOUR EVENT - CHICAGO.

Lead Manager / Assistant to World Tour Staff Director.

March 2016, March 2015, April 2014

Worked directly with client managing Leads and teams of up to 160 BAs with several different positions at Mccormick Center.

**Keurig Kold Sampling-Program** 

BOOKEDOUT. December 2015

**Motive Group** 

Mountain Dew Low BDI F.M. Manager. February 2015 - October 2015

**Push Models** 

December 2014 Lacoste Holiday Program Promo Model

**IBG** 

Miami Autoshow - StateFarm Specialist November 2014

Latinsphere **US Cellular/ Disney Tours** 

Bilingual Field Marketing Manager May 2009 / November 2014

Responsible for coordinating market strategy and placement within each market. Onsite activities included site walkthrough, overseeing load-in and load-out, training and managing teams of brand ambassadors (Up to 25 employees), applying brand messaging and securing assets. Provided detailed reports with photos and consumer feedback after each event. Served as community relations liaison between client and target. Assisted several tours in multiple cities and states : Disneyland Resorts Bilingual Halloween Tour (September 2013), US Cellular Concert Series (10 cities from August to September 2013, and July to August 2014), Let the Memories Begin Tour (Disney World in 2011), ESPN.

**GMR Marketing** 

Event Sponsor Booth Manager for Cars.com at Chicago Autoshow February 2014 Brand Specialist for Event Sponsor Booth Esurance at SoBe Food and Wine F. February 2014

**MKTG Nintendo Holiday Program** 

November to December 2013 Nintendo 3DS / Wii U Guru Manager (Chicago, IL) November to December 2012 Nintendo 3DS / Wii U Guru (Chicago, IL)

The Marketing Arm

Nintendo Wii U Summer Tour NINTENDO Guru (6 Cities Tour in the US) June to August 2014 NINTENDO Guru (Orlando, FL and Chicago, IL) July 2013 / August 2013

The Marketing Arm / USMP

Nintendo Wii U Experience Field Marketing Manager May 2012 / August 2012

Responsible for launch of Nintendo Wii U through several programs. Trained at Headquarters, was one of four managers at the 2012 E3 Nintendo Booth over viewing brand messaging and media relations. As a Field Market Manager helped launch the Wii U Experience Tour at different markets, trained local brand ambassadors on hardware and software titles and oversaw load-in and load-out. Launched the Wii U Lego City Undercover Experience at in Austin, TX.

**Azucar Enterprises Bailando con Verizon Wireless** 

Assistant Project Manager February 2012 to April 2012

**Phenomenon Worldwide** Unlock Affordable Modern Campaign

Project Manager September to December 2011

Responsible for overseeing the CB2 campaign Unlock Affordable Modern in three markets (Chicago, New York and Miami). Onsite activities included assisting event setup in store, training and managing teams of brand ambassadors (Up to 23 employees), applying brand messaging and, overseeing assets, Assured a fun environment at stores during event hours with targeted customers. Accomplished site walkthroughs and produced reports with photos and consumer feedback after each event. Served as community relations liaison between client and target.

Touring Brand Ambassador

June 2011 / August 2011

Educated consumers on 3D technology without the 3D glasses and presented the various entertainment capabilities of the Nintendo 3DS. Drove traffic to Warped Tour events and Nintendo Facebook page. Assisted Tour Managers in obtaining data for reporting including consumer comments, photos, etc.

## **EPS / Productions Plus / GC Marketing**

Product Specialist / Brand Ambassador

2005 / 2016

Scope of duties consisted of brand representation, implementation, and management of event marketing programs in Florida and Illinois for numerous blue-chip clients. Varied onsite activities included handling games, crowd control, brand messaging, product sampling and soft sales promotions. Clients include: Home Depot Bilingual Team, Fidelity Investments, American Express, Sony Playstation, Carhartt, U.S. Cellular, Verizon Wireless, The Coca-Cola Company, Toyota USA, Ford, Häagen Dazs, Cirque du Soleil, Bacardi, Stoli, McDonald's Corporation, Microsoft Xbox One, etc.

## Campaigners / ASM

Chicago, II

Sony Playstation Sales Specialist

August 2010 / February 2011

As a sales-focused Product Specialist helped drive measurable sales growth of Sony Playstation 3 and PSP consoles, video games and peripherals at select retail locations. Produced demos and constantly ranked among the top 10 in driven sales in the country. Responsible for several company assets.

**RMD Marketing** 

Product Specialist for Ford Ford Tour Emcee

Los Angeles, CA February 2008 / Nov. 2010 February / April 2008

Represented the Ford brand as a product specialist in a nationwide tour (Juanes La Vida Concerts) as well as TV shows (Oprah Show / Big Give) and Midwest local events ( NCLR, Self Magazine Workout in the Park ). As Emcee executed contests and brand messaging to large audiences in high prestige venues. Helped create thousands of impressions, did demos of the Ford Sync system and answered questions about the models in display. Scope of duties also included helping with logistics, maintenance of vehicles, lead capturing and impressions.

Campbell-Ewald

Tour Host Manager

Warren, MI

June / November 2008

Managed and scheduled guerilla marketing events in the South and Northeast regions for Carhartt line of work wear. Scheduled, managed and executed between 15 and 20 events a week at various types of workplaces which resulted in over 1 Million impressions. Supervised staff and wrote daily online reports for each event, collected and sent between 300 and 500 leads a week. Responsible for onsite activities, vehicle and equipment maintenance and security.

**Next Marketing** 

Atlanta, GA

**Product Specialist** 

Jan. 2008 / March 2008

Worked as part of a team of product specialists for Panasonic Living in HD Tour. Executed events at various retail stops in FL and GA and informed and educated atendees about various Panasonic HD products including Plasma TVs, Digital Cameras, Network Cameras, Laptops, etc. Helped with setup and tear down of event site containing tent with various multimedia kiosks.

#### Other Experiences

President and Co-owner of Import and Export Jewelry Business for two years, Miami Correspondent for International Media, Computing Instructor (for four years). Accomplished male model working with world's leading labels in the U.S., Italy and South America.

#### Languages

Fluent in English, Portuguese and Spanish. Basic knowledge of Italian and French.

#### **Skills**

Computer Sciences - Extensive computer experience and knowledge - including Microsoft Office Pro, Android and iOS. Excellent typing skills. Experience in import and export business, sales, customer service and customer support.

## References

Available upon request.